Remember...
牢記
There must be something that you always wanted to do but you couldn't.
一定有什麼想做但一直做不到的事情吧
There are many things I want to do.
我有很多想做的事
Very good.
很好
Whatever it is, however it is done,
不管是什麼事  無論要怎樣做
you will start doing it with utmost planning.
都要以做計畫開始
You should have daily, weekly, monthly plans.
應該有每日，每周，每月的計劃
You won't cut corners. You'll make it complicated.
不要走捷徑，要把事情做細緻
Dad, don't you remember anything?
爺爺  你不記得了嗎？
Dad, I'm getting a divorce.
爸  我要離婚了
I'll introduce you to someone.
我給你介紹一個人
But that's how he works.
但這就是他的工作方式
- Who is he? - That charlatan journalist, Ates Arbay.
-他是誰？-那個卑鄙的記者阿提斯·阿爾巴伊
I used to be a fiery and an idealist reporter.
我曾經是一個熱情的理想主義者
Oh, poor Agah.
哦，可憐的阿加.
What have you done?
你做了什麼？
AFTER 2 AM - CUSTOMERS LEAVE - THE DOORS ARE LOCKED
淩晨2點之後 -顧客離開 -鎖門
LIFE BEGINS SIGNED: AGAH BEYOGLU
簽名：阿加 貝尤魯
What do I do with him now?
我現在該怎麼辦？
They had "Nevra" written on their foreheads. What's with that?
他們的額頭上寫著“內芙拉”，這是怎麼回事？
Just a coincidence. It has nothing to do with me.
隻是巧合  與我無關
Selim, I actually have a question.
塞利姆，我有一個問題
Do you know someone named Naimhan Turedi?
你知道有人叫納伊姆漢 ·圖雷迪嗎？
- Naimhan... - Turedi. Born in Kambura.
-納伊姆漢- ·圖雷迪出生於坎佈拉
Oh yes, of course I do.
哦，是的，我知道
Yasin used to collect trash over by the garage. He's dead now.
Yasin以前經常在車庫裏收集垃圾  他已經死了
They had sons. Not good for anything.
他們有個兒子，冇什麼用處
They all left for Istanbul.
他們都去了伊斯坦佈爾
How about someone named Mehmet Yurtgil? A judge.
叫穆罕默德·尤爾吉爾的法官怎麼樣？
- He was assigned to here? - No. He might've passed by, though.
-他被分配到這裏嗎？-不，他可能已經過身了
I don't remember the name.
我不記得這個名字
Alright.
好的
I'll speak to the guys over at the station.
我要去跟警局的人聊一聊
Come by again, though, this time for dinner.
晚上過來吃飯
Don't even think about going back before stopping by one last time.
你不來的話就別想回去
Sure.
好的
Where's Agah Beyoglu? He's my dad. Where's my dad?
阿加 貝尤魯在哪裏，他是我父親
He was discharged.
他出院了
Discharged? When?
出院了？什麼時候？
He was right there when I went to sleep. I wake up and he's gone.
我睡覺的時候他就在那裏，我醒來之後他就不見了
When was he discharged?
他什麼時候出院的？
Ms. Zuhal, your father left in a hurry. He left you a note.
祖哈爾女士，您的父親匆忙離開，他給您留了張紙條
- Dad? - Over here.
-爸爸？-在這
What are you doing, dad?
爸  你在做什麼？
How about I don't share the details?
我不分享細節怎麼樣？
What is this note? Huh?
這是什麼紙條？
"I'm going to get the car. See you at the house."
“我要去取車，家裏見”
We were worried sick. You should've let us know.
我們都很擔心你，你應該讓我們知道的
I'm not used to letting people know.
我不習慣讓別人知道
I haven't been letting anyone know anything since your mother died.
自從你母親過身以來，我一直冇有讓任何人知道任何事情
That's some excuse!
那是個借口！
We were worried sick about you! How about some thoughtfulness?
我們真的很擔心你！考慮下我們好嗎？
You should really stop shouting. I can't hear you anyway.
別喊了，反正我也聽不見
KILLER OR VICTIM?
是殺手還是受害者？
KAMBURA POLICE DEPARTMENT
坎佈拉警察署
Nevra? Welcome!
內芙拉！歡迎！
It's me, Vural.
是我，烏拉爾
- Vural? - See?
-烏拉爾 -你看
Once someone leaves Kambura, they forget all about their past.
一旦有人離開了坎佈拉，他們就把以前的事情都忘了
You're hurting me.
你太傷我心了
- Vural. - Yes, Vural.
-烏拉爾 -是的，烏拉爾
Sorry, didn't recognize you.
抱歉，冇認出你
Of course not. Istanbul is another world.
當然了，伊斯坦佈爾是另一個世界
We've been reading all about you on the newspapers, though.
不過，我們一直在報紙上看有關你的消息
I saw you driving earlier today, but you were gone before I could say hi.
我看到你今天早些時候在開車，但在我打招呼之前你走了
Welcome.
歡迎
Thanks.
謝謝
- How's Aunt Nesrin doing? Well, I hope? - Sure.
-內斯林姨媽過得好嗎？-很好
Don't you worry. I'll take care of it.
放心吧，我會自己修的
Excuse me?
什麼？
Your door. I'll get it fixed.
車門，我會自己修的
What a shame.
真抱歉
I can take care of it.
我來修吧
Come on...
算了……
You're not coming back to Kambura anytime soon.
你不會很快回來坎佈拉的
You shouldn't.
你不會的
At least let me pay for it.
至少讓我付錢給你吧
Your money's no good here.
你的錢在這裏冇有用
- Anyway, goodbye. - Goodbye.
-總之，再見了 -再見
Agah! Come out!
阿加！出來！
Isn't Istanbul real expensive? How can you make it with your salary?
伊斯坦佈爾房價不是很貴嗎？薪水怎麼可能付得起？
I make do.
我付得起
Any information?
有任何信息嗎？
Can't find anything. He left Kambura a long time ago.
什麼都找不到  他很久以前就離開了坎佈拉
It's been years.
已經好幾年了
No info whatsoever since they've left.
從他們離開之後，冇有任何信息
But I'll tell the guys to keep looking.
但是我會告訴大家繼續尋找
We'll let you know if we have something.
如果有消息我們會通知您
So how do you make it? Do you rent your place?
那你怎麼做的？租房子嗎？
Agah!
阿加！
Come out!
出來！
Agah! You can't hide from me!
阿加！你躲不過我！
I'll burn this whole place down!
我會把整個地方都燒掉！
Come on, join us.
來吧，我們一起吃
So...
那麼……
Does Kambura feel any different?
坎佈拉有什麼變化嗎
Not at all. It's exactly the same.
完全冇有，還是老樣子
I recall when you used to be a little girl.
我記得你小時候
How old were you?
你那時候幾歲？
Ten.
十
I've been courting your mom ever since then. She's never interested.
從那以後我一直在嚮你媽媽示愛，她一直不感興趣
I'm not surprised.
意料之中
I'll kill you.
我要殺了你
You're being too much.
你太過分了
Salih...
薩利赫...
Come on, let me go.
好了，讓我走吧
We can go our separate ways.
我們可以各走各的
Besides, you're wounded. Don't let it get infected.
另外你受傷了，小心感染
You're the one who shot me, you lunatic!
是你先開槍打我，你個瘋子！
It was a mistake! It was an accident!
那是誤會，純屬意外！
You shot me point blank! How is that an accident?
你直接嚮我開了槍！怎麼會是意外呢？
How did you find me? Have you been following me?
你是怎麼找到我的？你一直在跟蹤我嗎？
Why would I be following you?
我為什麼要跟蹤你？
My car broke down and you were the first car to come by!
我的車壞了，你是第一輛駛來的車！
It was a coincidence! It was fate!
真是巧合！是天意！
I'm putting the gun away.
我把槍收起來
See?
看到？
I've put it away. See?
我把槍收起來了，看到了嗎？
Come on, you put yours away, as well, Salih.
好了，你也把你的收起來吧，薩利赫
Salih...
薩利赫...
Come over and let's talk, brother to brother.
過來，讓我們聊一聊
Come on.
來吧
Remember our conversations back in Kambura?
還記得我們在坎佈拉的談話嗎？
You're like a brother to me. Come on, don't do this.
你就像我的兄弟，來吧，別這樣
Salih...
薩利赫...
I used to go to the post office every day. Just to see your mom.
我以前每天去郵局隻是為了看看你媽媽
I used to send fake letters.
我曾經寄假信件
But I never got the chance to meet her.
但是我一直冇有機會見到她
One day, they told me she'd left.
突然有一天，他們告訴我她已經離開了
It had only been six or seven months since she'd started here.
她來這裏才六、七個月
- She left so soon. - It was a year. We stayed for a year.
-她這麼快就走了 -一年，我們住了一年
Give or take.
差不多吧
I never got to meet her then, but I got her in the end, after all.
之後再冇見到過她，但最終我還是得到了
It's delicious.
很好吃
Enjoy.
吃吧
Salih...
薩利赫
Come on, let's have a chat. We're brothers.
來吧，我們聊聊吧，好兄弟
Salih...
薩利赫...
Tell me, why?
告訴我為什麼？
Why did you come after me after all these years?
這麼多年過去了，你為什麼要找我？
Why did you try to kill me?
你為什麼要殺我？
What did I do to you?
我對你做了什麼？
That's funny.
真好笑
- That's what Naimhan asked. - Naimhan?
-那也是納伊姆漢問的問題 -納伊姆漢？
What did you do to him?
你對他做了什麼？
What did you do to Naimhan?
你對納伊姆漢做了什麼？
Tell me!
告訴我！
Salih, if this is the end of the road...
薩利赫，如果這是我的終點……
Then let me do it.
那就讓我自己來吧
- Drop your gun. Drop it! - I'm not dropping it.
-放下槍！-我不會放的
I'll fuck you up! Drop it!
你他媽的快放下！
I won't let you die before telling me why you tried to kill me.
在告訴我為什麼要殺我之前，我不會讓你死
Tell me, why!
告訴我為什麼！
Why were you after me?
你為什麼找我？
Conscience.
良心
Conscience?
良心？
What conscience? What does that have to do with anything?
什麼良心？良心和這有什麼關係？
You know what conscience means, don't you?
你知道什麼是良心，對嗎？
Fuck you and your conscience!
去尼瑪的良心！
You won't look me in the eye?
你都不好好看我一眼嗎？
It's been three years.
已經三年了
You haven't come to visit for three whole years.
你已經三年冇來了
You kicked me out.
你把我踢出去的
You haven't even called.
你甚至都冇有打電話
You told me not to.
你告訴我不要打
I did, because you left that cushy job and went and became a cop!
是啊，因為你辭掉了那份輕鬆的工作，去當警察了!
What was all that education for?
這些教育是為了什麼？
See what it's come to?
你看現在怎麼樣？
You might've gotten yourself into trouble.
你會惹上麻煩的
Your name, written on the foreheads of dead men.
你的名字，寫在死者的額頭上
Nevra...
內芙拉...
I worked my ass off to get you through school.
我努力工作供你上學
I had to work as a cashier in addition to my day job.
我除了日常工作外還要做出納員
When that didn't do it...
但當那些冇起作用的時候…
You got married four times.
你結了四次婚
- I did it all for you. - For me?
-那都是為了你 -為我嗎？
- So that you had a dad. - So that I didn't become a whore.
-那樣你能有一個父親 -因此我就不會成為妓女
Go on, say it. That's what you've always said.
繼續說吧，這就是你一直說的
You were so scared I'd go astray. I never figured out why.
你好怕我會誤入歧途  我一直不明白為什麼
Do you want to become a whore?
你想成為妓女嗎？
Why?
為什麼？
Why would I?
我為什麼會想？
You must've seen something deep within me.
你一定在我內心深處看到了什麼
- Don't be silly. - You must have.
-別傻了 -你一定有
That's enough!
夠了！
You got married four times for me!
你為我結了四次婚！
You saved me!
你救了我！
That was so selfless of you!
你真無私！
So selfless of you to always have a man around the house.
如此無私的你總會在屋子裏圍著一個男人
All you did to keep me from becoming a whore...
你做的一切都是為了不讓我變成妓女……
Getting with new men before even leaving the last one.
在離開上一個人之前就與新男人相處
Shut up.
閉嘴
By the way...
順便說說
I know you didn't ask, but my father's doing fine.
我知道你冇問，但是我父親很好
He didn't say hi, but he's fine.
他冇有打招呼，但很好
You still call him your father?
你還稱他為你父親嗎？
Your father's dead.
你父親死了
That bastard called Yuksel...
那個叫尤克塞爾的混蛋
He isn't half the man your father was.
他不及你父親的一半
He's the one who gave you these ideas.
是他給了你這些想法
He's the one who made you into a cop.
是他讓你成為了警察
Why so angry, mom?
媽媽你為什麼這麼生氣？
Huh?
?？
Tell me, why do you hate life so much?
告訴我，你為什麼這麼討厭生活？
Why don't you love me?
你為什麼不愛我？
Stop speaking nonsense.
別胡說
Then tell me you do.
那你告訴我
Say "I love you, my girl."
說“我愛你，我的女孩”
By the way, I hate the word "whore", you know.
順便說一句，我討厭“ 妓女”這個詞
It feels so dirty when I say it.
說出來就覺得髒
You're the only one I can say it to.
我隻能對你說這個詞
I become someone else when I'm with you.
當我和你在一起時我變得不像我
Like a child. A naive, innocent child.
像孩子一樣，天真無邪的孩子
You do that to me.
這就是你對我的影響
I love you too, mom.
媽媽  我也愛你
I love you too.
我也愛你
What's the emergency?
什麼緊急情況？
I had a heart attack.
我得了心髒病
- Alright. Come on in. - Thank you.
-好吧，進來 -謝謝
A heart attack?
心髒病？
How's he doing now?
他現在還好嗎？
He's fine, he just needs some rest.
他很好，他隻需要休息一下
The doctor said his heart was strong.
醫生說他的心很強壯
He's too full of anger to die.
他滿腔怒火，還不能死
I was in the hospital, but something urgent came up.
我在醫院裏，但是出了一些緊急情況
I had to do that. I had to get there.
我必須要去做一件事
But on my way there, I forgot what I was supposed to do.
但是在去那裏的路上，我忘記了應該做什麼
Mr. Agah...
阿加先生
Excuse my bluntness, but you'd had a heart attack.
原諒我的直言不諱，但你得了心髒病
You were in the hospital. What could've been so urgent?
你在醫院裏有什麼緊急的事？
It was my daughter Zuhal's birthday. I had to get her a present.
那是我女兒祖哈爾的生日，我有禮物要送給她
- Your daughter's here? - I'm here now.
-你的女兒在這裏？-我現在在這裏
Looking for a job.
找工作
Still haven't found one.
什麼都冇找到
Not sure what I'll do.
不知道我該怎麼辦
I'd like to meet her.
我想見見她
- We haven't even spoken on the phone. - I know.
-我們甚至都冇有打電話 -我知道
I'll come by unannounced, you know.
你知道我會不請自來的
It's not the end of the world.
這不是世界的盡頭
- If you're unhappy, then get divorced. - I guess that's what we'll do.
-如果你不開心，那就離婚 -我想這就是我們要做的
I told Mebrure so many times to divorce him, but she wouldn't listen.
我跟梅佈魯雷說過很多次讓她離婚，但她不聽
- We don't listen, sometimes. - Did it both to herself and to us.
-人們有時候就是不聽 -自找苦吃
- I was collateral damage, as well. - My mom and dad were miserable.
-對我也有附帶傷害 -我的父母都很痛苦
My dumb sister.
我愚蠢的妹妹
- Being dumb isn't good. - I'm in love, she said.
-裝傻是不好的 -我戀愛了，她說
- I'm not even in love. - Your mom was so naive.
-我根本冇有戀愛 -你媽媽太天真了
- She would believe anything. - I don't believe, though!
-她什麼都相信 -但我不相信！
So what?
所以呢？
I used to lie all the time, doc.
我以前一直撒謊，醫生
When I was young.
我小的時候
I used to lie so often, it was second nature to me.
經常撒謊，這對我來說是第二天性
It was almost a mania.
快要瘋了
Mebrure used to believe anything I'd say.
梅佈魯雷曾經相信我會說的話
Deceiving her started feeling horrible.
後來欺騙她讓我感到害怕
I hated myself.
我恨自己
I promised I'd never lie to her again.
我保證不會再對她說謊
I'd be as honest with everyone else as I was with myself.
我會像對待自己一樣誠實對待其他人
Alas...
唉……
Once I was cursed with this disease...
一旦我被這種疾病詛咒
This forgetting disease called Alzheimer's...
這種稱之為阿爾茨海默氏病的讓人遺忘的疾病
That's when I started lying again.
我又開始撒謊了
You know what's the worst part about being a liar?
你知道做為騙子最糟糕的是什麼？
Having to remember all the lies.
必須記住所有的謊言
What am I supposed to do now?
我現在該怎麼辦？
Call your cousin. We can call him together.
給你錶哥打電話，我們可以一起打電話給他
He'll find you a job that suits you. OK?
他會找到適合你的工作，好嗎？
You don't need your father. I'm right here for you.
你不需要留在你父親身邊，我就在這裏
He's the one who needs us.
是他需要我們
He's never accepted it, but he's always been the one who needs us.
他一直都不承認，但他才是需要我們的人
He thought he could do no wrong.
他以為他不會做錯事
Mebrure gave him everything she had.
梅佈魯雷把一切都給了他
I'm losing my personality.
我正在失去我的人格
It's too much to bear.
太讓人受不了了
Here's what we'll do.
接下來我們這樣做
- You can't bear the truth, you lie. - Yes.
-你不能忍受真相，你在說謊 -是的
- We'll discover that moment together. - How are we going to do that?
-我們會一起發現那一刻的 -我們怎麼做？
The moment you started running from reality.
從現實出發的那一刻
And why you keep running.
以及為什麼你一直在逃避
That's what we'll go looking for.
那就是我們要尋找的
But I don't know why.
但我不知道為什麼
You might not know.
你可能不知道
But your memory does.
但是你的記憶知道
Ask your memory.
問問你的記憶
Go into the past.
回顧過去
Go to the places that remind you of your past.
去那些能讓您回想起過去的地方
Whatever it is that's scaring you
不管是什麼使你恐懼
is hidden in your past.
都隱藏在你的過去
Find it, Mr. Agah.
找到它，阿加先生
Find the first truth that terrified you.
找到令你恐懼的真相
INCOMING CALL ATES ARBAY
阿提斯來電
Yes, Ates?
餵，阿提斯？
Is it time yet?
到時間了嗎？
Time for what?
什麼時間？
You've promised me an interview. Can we do it tonight?
您答應我的訪談，今晚可以做嗎？
I'm busy, Ates. Another time.
我很忙，再約時間吧
I didn't let you down the last time you called.
上次你找我的時候我可冇讓你失望哦
Fine. Where do we meet?
好吧，我們在哪裏見麵？
Give me some space, please.
請給我一些空間，謝謝
- Huh? - Take off.
-嗯？-走開
Take off where?
去哪裏？
I'm expecting someone. There's an empty seat over there.
我在等人，那邊也有座位
I'm not going anywhere!
我哪都不去！
My dearly departed wife will be here soon.
我親愛的亡妻很快就要來了
Go on.
去吧
Mebrure!
梅佈魯雷!
I saw that.
我看見了
Don't you have enough?
還冇拍夠嗎？
Don't look into the camera. Look over there.
不要看鏡頭  看那邊
That's the last one.
很快結束了
Just like that.
就這樣
Keep that pose.
保持這個姿勢
Is it done?
好了嗎？
No.
冇有
Stay just like that.
保持住
Just like that.
就這樣
Stay...
別動
Almost there...
快好了……
I've got it.
拍完了
Finally.
總算好了
Let's get started on that interview.
讓我們開始這次訪談吧
Deva?
德瓦？
Where have you been, Deva?
你去哪了？
I told my mom I was going out.
我告訴媽媽我要出去
She didn't ask where you'd be?
她冇有問你會去哪裏？
- I don't explain myself anymore. - Who did you take after, I wonder.
-我不再為自己辯解了 -我不知道你像誰
- You're so weird. - I know.
-你好奇怪 -我知道
You know...
你知道……
I've been hearing about
我經常聽說
increased drug use among teenagers.
青少年吸毒人數一直在增加
- You don't do that, right. - Of course not, grandpa.
-你不吸毒，對吧？ -當然不吸
Good. That's good to hear.
很好  很好
How about booze?
喝酒嗎？
Only if you're buying.
你買我就喝
I've got it. Thank you.
我知道了，謝謝
I want to speak to your former colleagues, as well.
我還想跟你以前的同事聊聊
From the company you used to work for.
你曾經工作過的公司
You can ask me whatever you'd like to know.
你想知道什麼可以直接問我
Why?
為什麼？
Because I know them all, but none of them know me.
因為我了解他們，但冇人了解我
Fine. Tell me something you'd like to tell me.
很好，告訴我一些你想告訴我的事
That's the only question that fits someone like you.
那是唯一適合你的問題
What would you like to say, Nevra?
你想告訴我什麼事？
What have you been up to today?
今天做了些什麼啊？
Today...
今天
I went to the place where I proposed to your grandmother. It was 40 years ago.
我去了40年前我嚮你祖母求婚的地方
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
- 謝謝你 -不客氣
Though.
雖然
I didn't propose this time.
這次冇有求婚
What I'd like to say...
我想說什麼
Is that I'm going to get that killer.
我要抓到那個殺手
Wherever he runs to.
無論他跑到哪裏
Wherever he hides.
無論他躲在哪裏
I'm going to find him, and arrest him.
我都要找到他並逮捕他
You don't believe me?
你不相信我嗎
I don't believe in anything anymore.
我什麼都不相信了
I don't even believe in myself.
我甚至不再相信自己
But I so need to believe in someone.
但是我需要相信一個人
I've been spending my years in the back pages of the newspaper
我多年來一直在報紙的封底上度過
in that DJ booth,
在那個DJ位上
at those receptions I attend just to get fucked up,
在那些招待會上
at the shitty premieres of lame-ass movies.
在爛片的首映式上
Feels like I'm rotting from the inside.
感覺就像我由內而外腐爛
I can't even bear to look in the direction of those photos.
我甚至不忍心看那些照片的方嚮
You still keep them up.
你還留著它們
They're still there.
還在那裏
I told a lie that day. Maybe the first lie of my whole life.
那天我說了一個謊言，也許是我一生中的第一個謊言
"Mebrure," I said,
“ 梅佈魯雷，”我說，
"I'll make you happy."
我會讓你福祉
"Mebrure, take my hand, and let's get up off this bench,
“拉著我的手，讓我們從凳子上站起來
and -excuse my French-let's get the fuck out of here."
讓我們他媽的離開這裏” 原諒我說了髒話
Without a care in the world.
冇有一點牽掛
Or...
或者
"Mebrure, forget you ever knew me..."
“寶貝，忘了你曾經認識我”
I'm not made for marriage.
“我不是個適合結婚的人”
"I'll only make you unhappy."
“我隻會給你帶來不幸”
Something like that.
像這樣
You can't hold your liquor at all, can you?
你根本不能喝酒，是嗎？
You're already seeing double. Where are you...
你已經看重影了，你在哪……
Go talk to her. Go on.
去跟她聊天吧
Think about what you're going to say. You'll kick yourself later otherwise.
想好了再說話，不然你會後悔的
A miserable soul, desperate for attention.
一個悲慘的靈魂，渴望得到關註
The biggest favor you can do for such a sociopath is to talk about him.
你能為這樣的反社會變態做的最大的幫助就是談論他
But you've been on this case ever since the murders started.
但是，自謀殺案發生以來，您一直在關註這個案件
Isn't that a favor to him, then?
那不是對他有利嗎？
I'm a journalist.
我是記者
I have to inform the public.
我必須通知公衆
Ates, aren't you afraid at all that the murderer will target you?
阿提斯，你一點都不害怕兇手會把你作為目標嗎？
Look...
看
Just like he has his eyes on me,
就像他看著我一樣
I have my eyes on the perimeter of my house.
我也能在房子周圍看到你
Remember, no one can turn invisible.
記住，冇有人可以隱身
Least of all someone so deranged.
至少如此瘋狂的人不會
This is what I do, you see.
這就是我所做的，你看到了嗎
I'm in show business.
我在做演員
The show serves one purpose only... To make people forget.
錶演隻不過是為了讓人們忘記
I'm in the forgetting business.
我正在忘記事情
- You're being too harsh on yourself. - It's how it works.
-你對自己太苛刻了-這就是它的運作方式
Let's say there's a massacre somewhere.
假設某處發生大屠殺
There's an assassination, but the assassin never gets caught.
發生一次暗殺，但刺客從未被抓住
I make people forget about them.
我能讓人們忘記他們
Has there been a huge fraud? Call for me and I'll make them forget.
發生過大型詐欺案嗎？找我，我會讓他們忘記
How? How do you make them forget?
怎麼做？如何使他們忘記？
With stories such as this one about the murderer.
像這樣一個關於兇手的故事
I spin a fairy tale.
我編了一個童話故事
They all listen with bated breath.
大家都屏息靜聽
He gets caught and another one emerges.
他被抓了之後另一個人出現了
He gets caught, and another one.
又被抓了，然後又出現一個
I tell all their stories. But you know what I don't do?
我給他們講故事，但是你知道我不做什麼嗎？
How come so many people are licensed to carry guns?
為什麼這麼多人可以攜帶槍支?
How come people can access guns so easily?
為什麼人們可以如此輕易地獲得槍支?
I never talk about that.
我從冇說過
You got it?
你明白了嗎？
If you want to make people forget about the gun,
如果你想讓人們忘記槍
all you have to do is talk about the victim.
你所要做的就是談論受害者
But I'm not doing it anymore.
但我不再這樣做了
I've had it up to here.
到此為止
What will you do?
你會怎麼做？
May I curse?
我可以講髒話嗎？
I'll fuck them up.
我會幹他媽的
I won't let people forget.
我不會讓人們忘記
When did you decide on that?
你什麼時候決定的?
Today.
今天
As I was shooting you, to be precise.
準確地說，當我給你拍照時
You're so sweet.
你好騷啊
The car...
車！
Zuhal...
祖哈爾...
I've been thinking.
我一直在想
We should get you a place.
我們應該給你找個地方
A place of your own.
屬於你自己的地方
You'd both be more comfortable that way.
那樣你們倆會更舒服
He'll have his own room, at least.
他至少會有自己的房間
I can cover the rent until you get a job.
我能負擔租金直到你找到工作
When you said you'd been thinking, I thought you'd be like...
當你說你一直在想的時候，我以為你會像
"Let's sell the apartment downstairs and get you a place of your own."
“我把樓下的公寓賣了，給你找個地方住。”
Something like that.
像這樣
It's not like I haven't been doing that.
我不是冇想過
Number four, covered your high school.
四號房間，用於支付你高中的費用
Number six, your college.
六號，大學的費用
Number seven, your master's in London.
七號，你的倫敦碩士學位
Number three, as you know, went towards your mother's treatment.
如你所知，三號支付了你母親的治療費用
I'm all alone in this huge building now.
我現在一個人在這個巨大的大樓裏
- We still have Number eight, though. - I told you I rent that out.
-不過我們還有八號 -我告訴你我把它租出去了
We can tell the tenants we need to sell it. I can talk to them.
我們可以告訴租戶我們需要賣掉，可以和他們交談
You can't talk to them. They're using it for storage.
不能跟他們談，他們在用房間做倉庫
They live abroad.
他們住在國外
I can call them, then. Just give me their number.
我可以打電話給他們，給我他們的電話
Of course. We can sell this apartment, as well.
當然我們也可以賣這套公寓
You can put me in a home.
你可以把我放在家裏
Even better, you can put me out on the street.
也可以把我扔到大街上
Do you realize how selfish you sound?
你知道你聽起來有多自私嗎？
This building is named after your mother.
這座建築以你母親的名字命名
How can you be so ready to let it go?
你怎麼能這麼輕易放手？
We should be grateful to my departed grandfather, right?
我們應該感謝我已故的祖父，對嗎？
For giving this building to my mother.
謝謝他把這棟樓交給我媽媽
What would we do if he hadn't?
如果冇有他我們該怎麼辦？
What would you do? What would I? What would Deva?
你怎麼辦？我怎麼辦？德瓦怎麼辦？
Say what you mean to say.
說出來
What is it you'd like to say, exactly?
您到底想說什麼？
Don't stick your nose where it doesn't belong.
不要多管閒事
See how I don't stick my nose into your business?
學學我，從不多管閒事
See how I never ask about why you got divorced from your husband?
我從冇問過你為什麼與丈夫離婚？
See how I keep my mouth shut? How about you try it out for once?
學我怎麼閉嘴，你嘗試一下如何？
Ask me, dad.
問我啊
Ask me. Why don't you?
問什麼不問呢？
Why don't you ask?
你為什麼不問？
Ask me why Deva and I came here.
問我為什麼德瓦和我來這裏
Ask me why he wants to get divorced.
問我為什麼他要離婚
Come on! But you won't, will you?
來吧！但是你不會問，對嗎？
You know why you won't?
你知道為什麼你不會問嗎？
Because you hate listening to other people's problems.
因為你討厭聽別人的問題
It's the thing you hate the most.
這是你最討厭的事情
Someone telling you of their troubles.
別人告訴你他們的麻煩事
Dad...
爸
You can't even bear it when people are sick around you.
你甚至不能忍受周圍的人生病
Remember the times I had fevers as a kid?
還記得我小時候發燒嗎？
Remember what you did? Do you remember?
記得你做了什麼嗎？
I'll remind you. You left.
我來提醒你！你離開了！
You left the house.
你離開了家
I used to pray with all my might not to get sick.
我曾經盡力祈禱不生病
Not to get fevers so that my father didn't get mad at me.
不要發燒，這樣我的父親就不會生我的氣
You didn't look after mom, either.
你也冇照顧媽媽
The nurses did. I did. The doctors did.
護士照顧了，我和醫生照顧了
But you never did.
但是你從來冇有
You'd come to the hospital.
你去醫院
I'd tell you, "Dad, mom's dying."
我會告訴你，“爸爸，媽媽快死了”
You'd say "No."
你會說“不”
"She's doing great. Mom's doing great."
“她很好，媽媽很好”
Because that's what you want to hear.
因為那是你想聽到的
Everything's great. No problems whatsoever.
一切都很好冇有任何問題
Everything's perfect.
一切都很完美
I'll say it if it will help. We have no problems, dad.
如果有用的話，我就說出來  我們冇問題，爸爸
You're perfect. I'm perfect.
你是完美的  我是完美的
Deva's perfect.
德瓦也是完美的
Life's perfect.
完美的人生
Good.
好
That's good.
那很好
Agah Beyoglu.
這裏是阿加 貝尤魯
- Agah? - Nukhet!
-阿加？-努赫特！
How are you?
你好嗎？
I was just thinking about you.
我剛剛還在想你
I was able to find some tickets.
我搞到了幾張票
- Were you now? - It's tonight. Would you like to join me?
-是嗎？-今天晚上你想一起嗎？
Sure.
當然
- What is it? - We're ready.
-什麼事？-我們準備好了
I'll be right there.
我馬上到
Hand these out to the guys.
把這些交給他們
Alright...
好了……
Where's Nevra?
內芙拉呢？
She got a tip from somewhere. She went to the courthouse to look into it.
她從某個地方得到了線報，去了法院進行調查
You know Mehmet Yurtgil, the judge?
你知道穆罕默德·尤爾吉爾嗎？
He was known for taking bribes.
他因受賄而聞名
She's looking into the suspects that were wronged.
她在調查被冤枉的嫌疑犯
She thinks someone might've took revenge on him.
她認為有人可能會對他報仇
Alright then. Anyway,
好吧，不管怎樣
I have the ballistics report right here. Here's the situation:
我這裏有彈道報告，結果是這樣：
The gun that was used to kill Naimhan Turedi
用來殺死納伊姆漢 ·圖雷迪的槍
does not match the one used to kill Mehmet Yurtgil.
與用來殺死穆罕默德·尤爾吉爾的那隻不匹配
That gun wasn't registered anywhere. However...
那槍冇有在任何地方註冊
We have some leads on the gun that was used to kill Naimhan Turedi.
我們在用來殺死納伊姆漢 ·圖雷迪的槍上有一些線索
Someone was shot and wounded with that gun in 2001.
2001年有人用那把槍開槍並受傷
The gun was seized, and is supposed to be
槍應該是被冇收了
in the Ard谋chan municipality police department's evidence locker.
存放在阿迪坎市警察局的證據儲物櫃中
But it's gone! Why's that?
但是它消失了，為什麼呢？
Because that evidence locker no longer exists.
因為那個證據儲物櫃已經冇有了
How about... That sleazeball you were looking into?
你調查的那個混蛋怎麼樣？
He had nothing to do with it.
他跟這些都冇有關係
Alright. Now...
好吧……
The individual who did all this shit...
做這些事的人
Let's call him Tufan for now.
我們暫時叫他圖凡
Tufan gets into the evidence locker.
圖凡進入證據儲物櫃
He burglarizes the locker. Then...
他盜竊了儲物櫃，然後
He burns the place down to make it look like the mafia did it.
他把地方燒了，使它看起來像黑手黨做的一樣
So he's not interested in killing just anyone.
所以他對殺人不感興趣
He's not a regular serial killer.
他不是常規的連環殺手
Since he's in possession of so many guns,
既然他擁有這麼多槍，
and assuming he's not interested in selling them,
並假設他不準備賣槍
welcome to your own personal hells.
那麼就很明顯了
He's going to commit a massacre.
他將要開始屠殺
Unless we catch him first.
除非我們先抓到他
MARCH 18 SUNDAY
3月18日 周日
Here. Here's my resum茅.
這是我的簡曆
Thank you for agreeing to see me. I know you're busy.
謝謝你同意見我  我知道你很忙
It's an honor to meet you.
很榮幸見到你
This means nothing.
這冇什麼意義
This is it.
就是這個
- Where have you been? Austria? - Australia.
-您去過哪裏？奧地利？-澳洲
I just got back.
我剛回來
You're just in time.
你來的很及時
Melahat, my secretary for 20 years,
我的秘書跟了我20年了，
was retired just last week.
上周剛剛退休
Coincidence, I guess.
我猜是巧合吧
There are no coincidences.
冇有巧合
Because life itself is a coincidence.
因為生活本身就是巧合
A man locks the door to his house for 99 days.
一個人連續鎖門99天
On the 100th day, he forgets to lock the door.
在第100天，他忘記鎖門
The thief repents.
小偷很後悔
He ignores the house for those 99 days,
在那99天內，他無視這所房子，
but finds the door unlocked on the 100th day.
但在第100天發現門冇鎖
The days line up.
每天都排著隊
What do you call that?
你怎麼說？
A coincidence?
巧合？
No.
不是
What is it?
那是什麼？
It's life.
這就是生活
You're a fast learner, Zuhal.
你學得很快  祖哈爾
- Celik. - Beyoglu. My surname's Beyoglu.
-塞利克 - 貝尤魯  我姓貝尤魯
I'm getting divorced.
我要離婚了
Do you know Agah Beyoglu? Is he a relative of yours?
你知道阿加 貝尤魯嗎？他是你的親戚嗎？
He's my father.
他是我父親
Incredible.
難以置信
Now this, this isn't life. This is coincidence.
這不是生命這是巧合
How is he doing? Well, I hope?
他最近好嗎？
He's well, of course. How do you know him?
他很好，當然，你怎麼認識他？
From Kambura. Where else?
當然是坎佈拉  還能是哪裏？
- Prosecutor? - Did you know about this?
-檢察官？-你知道這件事嗎？
KILLER OR VICTIM?
是殺手還是受害者？
I did. It was Nevra's idea. I told her to go ahead with it.
我知道  那是內芙拉的主意  我告訴她繼續做下去
That was a stupid risk to take.
這是一個愚蠢的冒險
What if Tufan gets caught and everything is revealed?
如果圖凡被抓了並且一切都暴露了怎麼辦？
What then?
然後會怎樣呢？
Tufan has no connection either to Nevra or to any of the victims.
圖凡與內芙拉或任何受害者都冇有任何關係
That's why I approved the news article.
所以我批準了這篇新聞
There's someone else involved.
還有其他人參與
Whoever it is that's helping Tufan
不管是誰在幫圖凡
will panic when he realizes that we're on his trail.
當他意識到我們在追蹤他時，他會感到恐慌
It's your call.
是你的電話
But I'm uneasy.
可是我很不安
I'm not sure getting Nevra involved in this was the right idea.
我不確定讓內芙拉參與這個案子是否正確
Do you have any better ideas? No?
您有更好的主意嗎？
Then we proceed.
那我們繼續
Did you tell Firuz?
你有冇有告訴菲魯茲？
I did. He's supervising Nevra.
告訴他了  他在監督內芙拉
Where's Nevra now?
內芙拉現在在哪裏？
I told her she'd be kicked off the force if it was discovered.
我告訴她如果被發現  她會被踢出警隊
She's lying to me. Told me her mom was sick. Went to Kambura.
她對我撒謊  告訴我她媽媽生病了  去了坎佈拉
That's where she lives.
那是她家
Isn't there where the second victim was born?
第二個受害者不就是在那裏出生的嗎？
That's right. She could be looking into it.
是的  她可能正在調查
Good. We have some leads, then.
好  我們有了一些線索
We do but I can't bear the thought of using one of my people as bait.
但我不忍心用我的人當誘餌
Are you having her followed? You are. So what's the problem?
你不是有人在跟著她嗎？有什麼不放心的？
Look here, Tolga.
註意  托爾加
He's not going to stop killing people anytime soon.
他近期不會停止殺人
Who's supposed to catch him? You are.
誰應該抓住他？是你
What's the only lead we have? Nevra.
唯一的線索是什麼？內芙拉
If you take Nevra off the case,
如果你將內芙拉拒之門外，
it won't matter whether it was Tufan or someone else.
不管是圖凡還是其他人
You'll never catch the murderer.
你永遠都不會抓住兇手
Someone's committing these murders just to get Nevra to try to solve them.
有人犯下這些謀殺罪隻是為了讓內夫拉設法解決他們
MAYA'S COSTUME WORLD
瑪雅的裝扮世界
Those things will kill you, you know.
煙會殺死你的，你知道吧
You don't have to throw it out. Give me one.
別扔，給我來一支
- Any leads from the courthouse? - No.
-法院有線索了嗎？-冇有
I have a light.
我有火
My father's lighter.
我父親的打火機
He passed it down to me the day he stopped smoking.
他戒煙的那一天把它傳給了我
I asked him what I was supposed to do with it. I didn't even smoke.
我問他我該怎麼辦，我那時還冇開始抽煙
I picked it up that day.
我在那天開始抽煙
I picked up smoking the day my father quit. Ridiculous.
我父親戒煙那一天我開始抽煙
It was my mom that encouraged me to smoke, actually.
實際上是我媽媽鼓勵我抽煙
She told me it was alright if I smoked, but that I shouldn't be sneaky about it.
她告訴我如果我抽煙是可以的，但是不應該偷偷摸摸
I didn't smoke, but I couldn't tell her.
我不會抽煙，但是我不能告訴她
I sat across from her and lit one up just to get to spend some time with her.
我坐在她的對麵，點燃了一根煙，與她共度時光
That's how I started smoking.
我就是這樣開始吸煙的
Just to do the same thing as her at the same time as she did.
隻是為了和她在一起做點什麼事
How is she? Better?
她好嗎？
Better. She's better.
好多了
It must be hard, living so far away from each other.
應該很難吧，彼此相距太遠
- I see her from time to time. - Good. Don't stop seeing her.
-我時不時能見到她 -好  不要不見她
My father's dead now.
我父親已經死了
This is all that's left of him.
這就是他剩下的一切
MUNIR - MY LOVELY CAT
尼穆爾 -我可愛的貓
I'm so scared of death, Munir.
我好怕死，穆尼爾
In fact, I'll tell you a secret.
其實我會告訴你一個秘密
I'd be OK with it even if everyone on earth died
即使地球上的每個人都死了，我也冇關係
and I were the only one left.
我是唯一剩下的一個
I mean...
我的意思是
I'm even willing to face such loneliness.
我甚至願意麵對這樣的寂寞
What if I still remember all I've done in the afterlife?
如果我來世還記得我所做的一切怎麼辦？
I couldn't bear that.
我不能忍受
I couldn't.
我不能
Grandpa!
爺爺！
What are you doing? Shut the door!
你在做什麼？關上門！
What...
什麼
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
Shut the door!
關上門！
Such bad timing.
來得真不是時候
Tell your mom I have some errands to run tonight.
告訴你媽媽  我今晚有事要出門
Get yourself a cell phone, please.
求你買個電話吧
I have a phone.
我有電話
By the way, let me introduce you guys. Suveyda, my grandfather.
順便給您介紹一下，這是蘇薇達
Nice to meet you.
很高興見到你
I hope you're using protection.
我希望你做了保護措施
I can't handle another child.
我無法應付另一個孩子
- I'm not staying. - What are you doing?
-我不能停車 -你在做什麼？
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
I forgot I had something to do.
我忘了我有事要做
I have something to do. I'd forgotten. I'm not coming in.
我有事  可做我忘了  我不能去了
You can make a u-turning side the car park.
你可以在停車場的另一邊掉頭
Could you tell the car behind me to let me pass in reverse?
你能告訴後麵那輛車的車主讓我倒車過去嗎?
There are too many cars waiting.
有太多車在等
- But I'm... - Open up your boot, please.
-但我……-請打開你的後備箱
But I'm in a hurry. That'll be a lot of wasted time.
但是我很著急  那會浪費很多時間
It's how the procedure works. I don't make the rules.
這是工作程式  規則不是我定的
The car doesn't run on natural gas, I assure you.
我嚮你保證，這輛車不是用天然氣發動的
I believe you, but I still have to look. Give me your keys, please.
我相信你，但我還是要看看  請把你的鎖匙給我。
The boot's broken. It doesn't open.
後備箱壞了  打不開
- Hand me your keys, please. - It's broken, I'm telling you.
-請把鎖匙交給我  -壞了，我告訴你
Fine. Give me a minute.
好  我等一下
Broken.
壞了
I've tried so many times, but it won't open.
我已經嘗試了很多次了，但是打不開
- Let me try, sir. - It won't open.
-讓我試試，先生  -它不會打開
- But, it won't open. - Let me try.
-但是，它打不開  -讓我試試
Look! You break it, you buy it.
看！你弄壞了，賠錢吧
- Forgive me, Hajji. - It's fine.
-請原諒哈吉（到麥加朝聖過的回教徒）  -算了
- I have to follow the orders. - I understand.
-我必須遵守命令  -我明白
My uncle's a Hajji as well. He just got back.
我叔叔也是哈吉  他剛回來
May Allah bless him.
願真主保佑他
Amen. Amen.
阿門  阿門
They say there's a killer on the loose. We have strict orders.
他們說有個殺手在逃  我們有嚴格的命令
How many times have I told you there was nothing to see?
我告訴過你很多次了  冇有什麼可看的
- Please forgive me for prying. - It's fine.
-請原諒  -很好
Nobody believes in people anymore.
人與人之間最基本的信任在哪裏
Such a tragedy!
真是悲哀！
Forgive me for being late, Nukhet.
努赫特，原諒我遲到了
I ran into so many delays.
我遇到了些麻煩事
- Don't mention it. You're here now. - You look great.
-別說了  你現在到了  -看起來很棒
- Thank you. So do you. - Thank you.
-謝謝你  你也是  -謝謝
- We should go in, it's about to start. - Of course. After you.
-我們快進去吧  快開始了 -當然，在您之後
- Welcome. - Good evening.
-歡迎  -晚上好
- Thank you. - Your seats are right over there.
-謝謝  -您的座位就在那邊
- Thank you, guys.
-謝謝  -謝謝你們
What's going on?
這是怎麼回事？
What are you doing? Who are you?
你在做什麼？你是誰？
Answer me!
回答我！
No mortal can take this life.
冇有人能奪走生命
They can't bear it.
他們不能忍受
They deny everything.
他們否認一切
They lie.
他們說謊
They keep quiet.
他們保持安靜
Or they throw it all up.
或丟棄
Or they plot.
或陰謀
Or they run from it.
或逃避
Or they steal.
或偷竊
Or they break.
或破産
Or they give birth.
或生育
Or they suffocate.
或窒息
Or they get drunk.
或醉酒
Or they fall in love.
或戀愛
Or they stop moving,
或停止
and die little by little.
一點一點地死去
They wilt.
他們枯萎
They question.
他們質疑
They get mad.
他們生氣
They get resentful.
他們不滿
They ejaculate.
他們射精
They seize up.
他們抓住
They believe.
他們相信
They get created.
他們創造
They fight.
他們打架
They get wounded.
他們受傷
They try...
他們嘗試
They try, and get it wrong.
他們嘗試然後錯了
They try,
他們嘗試，
and get it wrong.
然後錯了
Try and get it wrong.
嘗試弄錯
Conscience resembles the gut.
良心類似於內心
It keeps working away even while you're asleep.
即使您在睡覺時，它也在不停地工作
No matter how much you deny your conscience,
無論您有多麼否認自己的良心，
that horrible murder you've committed
你犯下的可怕的謀殺案
always becomes the rope you get hung by.
會永遠成為你被吊住的繩索
It wraps around your neck,
它纏繞在你的脖子上，
the oily pieces of rope your victim has for hands.
你受害者手上的油乎乎的繩子
You seldom know what it is you've murdered.
你基本不知道你殺的是什麼
But you still keep hanging yourself every night in your dreams.
但你仍然每天晚上都在夢中吊死自己
The gut resembles the conscience.
內心很像良心
If you're looking to empty it of its contents,
如果您要清空其中的內容
you'll find somewhere to do it.
你會找到一個地方做
Man...
人
Tries, and gets it wrong.
嘗試，並弄錯了
Man tries and gets it wrong.
人嘗試並弄錯了
Tries and gets it wrong.
嘗試並弄錯了
Agah, are you alright?
阿加，你還好嗎？
I can't take it anymore.
我受不了了
Tries and gets it wrong.
嘗試並弄錯了
This is art?
這是藝術？
Sorry.
抱歉
They call it art? What is this?
他們稱之為藝術？這是什麼？
Tries and gets it wrong.
嘗試並弄錯了
That's the first time I've left a play before the curtain.
那是我第一次在結束前離開
I thought it was ridiculous.
我認為這很荒謬
It's good that we left early. I was bored out of my mind.
幸好離開的早，我要無聊死了
I've been meaning to tell you something, but I've never found the right time.
我一直想告訴你一些事情，但是我一直冇找到合適的機會
When I came to visit you at the hospital, your daughter Zuhal was devastated.
當我來醫院看望您時，您的女兒祖哈爾似乎遭受了重創
- Did she say something inconsiderate. - No. Just the opposite.
-她說了些不體麵的話 -不，恰恰相反
She said something that moved me.
她說了一些讓我感動的事
You told her that you were staying over at my place that night you had your accident.
你告訴她那天晚上你在我家過夜了
You said I was your girlfriend.
你說我是你女朋友
At least that's the impression she'd gotten.
至少那是她的印象
- What did you say? - I said that you were with me.
-你說什麼？-我說你和我在一起
I'm sure you had your reasons.
我確信你有你的理由
- I wouldn't speak against you. - You're so kind.
-我不會揭穿你-你真好
Thank you.
謝謝
I've been living on my own for such a long time...
我獨居了很長時間
I've gotten used to it.
我已經習慣了
But it does get boring from time to time.
但有時也會變得無聊
I go out on my own sometimes,
有時候我一個人出去玩
but I don't want them to worry about me.
但我不想讓他們擔心我
Forgive me for putting you on the spot like that.
請原諒我那樣讓你為難
You know what I said to myself?
你知道我內心怎麼想嗎？
I wish he'd really stayed over.
我希望他真的能來我家
DEAR NEVRA ELMAS, WE WISH YOU A HAPPY BIRTHDAY. ARTI BANK.
親愛的內芙拉 埃爾馬斯，祝你生日快樂  阿提斯
This cake's delicious. Did you buy it?
這蛋糕很好吃  你買的嗎？
Yes, Selim. Enjoy.
是的，塞利姆  吃吧
I'll get you one on your birthday.
你生日那天我給你買一個
- When's that, by the way? - Don't worry about it.
-什麼時候？-別操心了
- About what we talked about... - What was that?
-我們討論過的…… -什麼？
That house on the hill?
那座山上的房子？
Nesrin hates talking about it, that's why I couldn't say anything.
內斯林討厭說起它，這就是為什麼我什麼也不能說的原因
But there was a tragedy there.
但是那裏曾發生過一起慘案
It was ten years ago.
十年前
You were away at college.
你去上大學了
A family came and moved in to that house on the hill.
一家人搬到山上的那所房子裏
Shortly thereafter, there were a few burglaries.
此後不久，發生了幾起盜竊案
Everybody blamed the new family.
每個人都怪罪新搬來的那家人
One night, the people worked themselves into a frenzy.
一天晚上，人們變得瘋狂起來
Young, old, everyone...
年輕人，老人，所有人……
They decided to drive the family away.
他們決定驅逐這家人
They surrounded the house.
他們包圍了房子
Shouting, throwing rocks...
大喊  並且扔石頭
The family was too scared to come out of the house.
那家人太害怕了不敢出門
And then, I don't know who, but someone threw a torch at the house.
然後，我不知道是誰，但是有人把火把扔到了屋子裏
It flared up...
點著了
and burned the house down.
把房子燒了
Five children inside.
裏麵有五個孩子
And the mom and dad.
還有爸爸媽媽
They all burned up.
他們都被燒死了
Who threw the torch?
誰扔的火把？
No one would talk.
冇有人會說
The police interrogated all of them, but no one would say anything.
警察審問了他們所有人，但是冇人願意說
It was completely forgotten after a while.
過了冇多久，就被完全遺忘了
Everyone had stopped talking about it.
每個人都不再談論
The house is still up there, burned to a crisp.
房子還在那兒，燒焦了
No one even bothered to tear it down.
甚至冇有人願意拆掉它
No one is bothered by it. They might walk by it,
冇有人為此煩惱  他們隻是路過
but they don't want to think about it, so they don't even notice it.
但他們不去想它，所以他們甚至都冇有註意到
Was Naimhan Turedi there on that night?
那天晚上，納伊姆漢 ·圖雷迪在那裏嗎？
Of course.
當然
All his friends, his relatives, everyone he knew was there.
他所有的朋友，他的親戚，他認識的每個人都在那裏
Sefer was there. Yakup and his uncle, as well.
塞費爾也在那  亞庫普和他的叔叔都在
They were drunk.
他們喝醉了
They'd gotten smashed at R谋za's place.
他們在雷紮的家喝醉了
How do you know about it?
你怎麼知道的？
It haunts my dreams.
我經常夢到
It didn't use to,
以前不這樣的
but people change as they get older.
但是隨著年齡的增長人們會改變
Easy to say...
說起來容易
Seven people were killed.
七人被殺
The children were so small.
孩子都還很小
Who threw the torch, Selim?
誰仍的火把，塞利姆？
I didn't see him!
我冇看到！
I...
我……
I only threw a single stone.
我隻扔了一塊石頭
Is this a bad time?
現在過去好嗎？
TODAY IS NEVRA'S BIRTHDAY I GOT HER A BIRTHDAY PRESENT
今天是內芙拉的生日  我有一件禮物送給她